All right. Uh
just a little bit of notes um because
people have reached out. First of all,
this um because this may be uh the last
week that I'm in Maine. Uh not sure yet.
I'm not sure whether I'll be recording
from here or Maine next week, but uh
I've been asked a lot of questions
particularly about uh Maine. And I just
want to give people who are getting to
know me, have seen me on podcasts. Uh
the reason I'm in Maine is because on
September 11th, 2001, and we're
approaching 25 years since September 1st
or September 11. Um many of you know the
best my best friend growing up and the
best man at my wedding died 911. Um I
ended up uh going back to Morgan
Stanley. I was a partner there already.
I was on the trading floor the day after
when the markets were closed uh
basically with other partners figuring
out how we were going to operate and run
business and uh very emotional obviously
and I got a phone call. I had made an
offer on a house in Maine because I had
taken my daughter up there, my oldest
daughter up to camp there. Fell in love
with the place. Reminded me of my father
um being the son of a a bluecollar
worker and being the son of a core
driller. Uh I just fell in love with the
place. I did not like the shores uh of
the area that I grew up in in New Jersey
and definitely not the Hampton's my
style. So, I fell in love with Maine. I
bought a home in Kenny Bunkport. Um
moved up there and I did the commute
there for about 15 years. I've moved
further north now to get away from the
people that found Maine. Uh but in the
background, people have asked about the
painting. The painting is a reference to
uh Shawn Christopher Shawn Kaitton who
was a caner who died. Uh, I bought that
painting after I moved to Maine. The
wine bottle behind me is the bottle that
I bought in Napa Valley, which is a
remembrance of 911. I turned the bottle
around this week. It has remembrance if
you guys want to blow it up. You've got
a Bernard King signed basketball there.
You've got my Nicks hat on. Sean and I
went to um many games. And then also
behind me is a photo of him and I at a
bar in the Bronx many hours after the
Yankees won the World Series uh where
Wade Bogs was riding the police horse.
Uh Maine is a special place for me. I
come up every year and since you guys
asked about it, I just wanted to go
through. Now on other notes for you guys
that have reached out, number one, I
will never reach out to you in WhatsApp
offering you trades or doing anything. I
will never do that in X. If you reach
out to me in LinkedIn, I may or may not
respond because I get hundreds of people
reaching out. Same thing goes in my
email. So don't take it personally if I
don't respond. Don't I'm never reaching
out to anyone. So, unless you're on the
subscriber emails, you're not getting
anything from me. I say that because
there's AI bots everywhere and people
impersonating me on every single
location. I tried to get rid of them for
a while. Didn't work. Um, on another
note, people that are sending me stuff
about what do you think about this
Goldman Sachs person or this Morgan Sax
person, the Gold Morgan Stanley person,
they have a different view on XYZ. Guys,
if you haven't learned anything watching
this, I don't care about anyone's
opinions. I care about everyone's
opinions, but not anyone's opinions. I
do my own work. I take all of the
information that I can together and then
I make a decision in a paramutual manner
where I go through the odds and I'm
trying to find things that people either
don't agree with me on. So, I'm
generally trying to be somewhat of a
contrarian, but at the same point, I'm
trying to find ideas that have good
riskreward. I will always be an
independent thinker. I will always be
flexible on my views. So, I'm going to
take you guys through that today cuz
some of you said that I'm only positive.
And if that's what you believe from the
subscriber list and if you ended up
buying the top of the market because you
subscribed and said, "Oh, this is a bull
market in something." I'm going to go
through and show you how to take all of
the transcripts I do and I'm going to
give you a prompt to incorporate it into
a way where you can take the
information. I'm just speaking from the
heart every single week. Guys, one thing
I will say repeatedly, we are in a
structurable market in the demand for
compute. It is insatiable. And until I
start hearing people that I respect on
Wall Street start recognizing that there
is no end ever coming up for the demand
for compute, just like there is no food
end. If we keep increasing people on the
planet by a billion every year, that we
will never catch up. The same thing for
compute. It is impossible to get enough
compute for all of the billions of
agents that are coming online that are
just starting. This is investing in
compute. So, this whole video today is
to some degree going to be about
compute. And that's why I'm going to go
back to the agenda side for this week.
Um, my job is to help your business,
whether you're an RAIA, whether you're
an asset manager, help you with
research, help you with independent
thinking, but also get you ready to help
your children adjust to this world
because it's coming fast and it's going
to be accelerating over the next
certainly 24 months. Crypto is going to
be a bigger part of the discussion. And
if you have no knowledge of crypto or no
understanding as to where it's going to
be, you're going to suffer in the next
12 months for sure. But certainly 24
months, you're going to have to adapt.
So we'll go through the recap. We'll go
through the compute. We'll go through
the token factories, Coreweave, Google,
SpaceX, their commentary. The AI regime
change, which has to do with the stuff
that I'm doing. And probably most
importantly, two things there. Number
six. Number nine. Number six, we are
going back to work, guys. The summer is
over. I'm heading back to New York. I
have spent a lot of time working. I've
tried to create prompts. I've created a
new website. There's a whole bunch of
things I've done um with AI agents,
which hopefully I've been able to give
you guys some stuff that has helped. But
the 2027 outlook is what I'm going to
start focusing on because next year is
about consumer agents. This year was
about agents, the agentic economy
opening. Next year is about consumer
agents and what they need, which is the
financial guardrails, which is where
crypto shows in. Number nine, be an
entrepreneur, not an academic. Academics
will continue to cost you money. Anyone
that is giving you history and analoges
and blah blah blah, especially
economists, I will take you through why
that is not worth your time. S&P up 40
basis points for the week.
IWM up 1%. Q's up 1%. The JV AI thematic
portfolio outperformed again, up 3% for
the week. We made new all-time highs in
most of the important indices and also
around the globe. uh the earnings and
again I'll continue to say it earnings
growth 51% for the S&P sales growth
probably the more important number up
15% year-over-year
I can't remember a time when we were in
a mature part of the economic cycle and
global UPS is something like 47%
year-over-year everywhere you look EPS
has been moving smartly higher
this is the critical thing if you start
believing in people that tell you this
is is an isolated bubble to a few tech
names in the US. It's not true. You've
got the whole globe breaking out in
terms of earnings per share, and that's
because time is changing. You're going
to hear me talk about this a lot. This
is going to provoke thought in you guys.
I will have a very important Substack
coming out. For you Substack readers,
the time is coming where I'm going to go
down to about once a month in my papers
because I'm entering in the crypto side
and most of the stuff is shifting to the
subscriber site for my crypto work. Um,
this is the MSCI World Bank index.
This is parabolic and going higher. This
is a reflection of what's happening with
AI. All of these charts are a reflection
of what's happening with AI. It is a
reflection of what's happening around
the globe. AI is disrupting all academic
research that you know. All the things
that you've believed in are breaking
down. And the reason is because
productivity is happening. more and more
of the smarter people with inside the
Fed that I read and the IMF and the
they're starting to recognize now again
it's got to be the younger people the
productivity boom is happening you have
to put it into context though earnings
are up 30% year-over-year in the S&P
forecast for this year this is our job
hiring zero
economists tell you the labor market is
strong they want the Fed to raise rates
this is all BS the labor market relative
to the way things move over time. We
should be hiring lots of people because
we're growing earnings, not coming out
of a recession like these periods at a
record pace.
So why aren't we hiring people? When I
was at Morgan Stanley, if we had
earnings growing rapidly, we'd be hiring
people. That's what you did. You threw
more money at more people. Not happening
anymore. And the reason is because we've
got enterprise agents which are coming.
Not having started yet. They're coming.
This does not mean we'll be losing
millions of jobs. But what it does mean
is we have job losses already. X
healthcare. We're already seeing small
job losses. That is productivity. We
don't need as many people. We're seeing
businesses set up. Startups are
happening. We're getting more business
formations. Jordy has a business.
All of this stuff. I don't work now for
a Fortune 500 company and I don't work
for a country a company with 100 people.
Started my own business. So consumer
agents are coming next year. This is the
token needs for them. This is what
they're paid in. This is what they eat.
This is what they need to survive. They
work 247
365.
They're shrinking time. So when you say
year overyear for anything now, that is
a human thing. Agents don't sleep.
Agents don't go to the bathroom. Agents
don't go to lunch. Agents don't go to
the pantry to flirt. Agents don't do any
of that stuff. So what you're left with
is token consumption is growing rapidly
and time is shrinking. So in the case of
year-over-year, the reason we're seeing
earnings grow so fast, the reason
nominal GDP at this point is at least
growing where it is because the math on
that is not correct, you have to focus
on the profit margins and you have to
focus on the earnings growth. Time is
shrinking. So we're now doing
effectively two times what it used to
take in one year and then eventually
it'll be three times and four times and
five times. And the reason is because
the agents are working all the time. Now
this doesn't mean that things go
parabolic in terms of the earnings. What
it means is the earnings continue to
outpace the prices because private
companies are doing a lot of this. They
are going to steal from the public
companies. We'll spend more time on
this. If you don't believe compute is
insatiable
right now, all of you know what coding
agents are. At least you should. If you
don't and don't know what I just said
about 247365,
well then we're going to get into
finally them actually being deployed.
They haven't even been deployed yet. We
just have the capability of using them.
Enterprise agents become persistent
digital labor. This will be happening
next year. Consumer agents will be
following in the latter part of next
year. This is your Jarvis. This is
people ordering things for you. This is
like your AMX uh uh assistant who does
everything for you. this is coming and
they'll be doing things while you sleep.
They'll be booking your travel. They'll
be ex orderering things for you.
Everything will be happening
instantaneously and we'll start reducing
the friction in the economy. Then you're
going to get into autonomous driving and
for that you need a world a world model
problem. We need a hell of a lot more
compute for that. We need a hell of a
lot more compute for humanoids. These
are all coming every single year. These
innovations used to take decades to
come, but now they're happening in such
a compressed amount of time because of
intelligence.
The numbers are staggering. Right now
we're in this part. So this year we
needed 10 to 100 times for the coding
agents relative to last year for
chatbots. That's why everything went
parabolic. Look at the stepup function.
Another 10 times. Then another 10 times.
It never ends guys. The amount of
compute we need never ends. We are
transitioning from systems that give
instant cash responses chatbot to
systems that plan, reason and simulate
outcomes before taking an action. This
is so complex. This is demos sabas. We
need magnitudes more compute. That's why
Jensen Yuan comes out and says, and he
only said this at the beginning of this
year, it's going to be AI factories, the
new infrastructure intelligence. We need
this is what we need to produce. This is
why there's compute futures. This is why
everything you're hearing is about, oh,
we need compute.
We need it endlessly to feed the new
billions of employees on the planet.
Jensen Yuong says comput is the new
economy. He said this at the Morgan
Stanley event in March.
Nvidia this week, AI factory computing
investable asset class. The reason we
know this is a fact is because Apollo,
Black Rockck, Blackstone, Brookfield,
Goldman Sachs, KKR to establish AI
compute infrastructure financing
platforms to mobilize over half a
trillion dollars of third party capital
to build the stuff that Nvidia needs.
They don't want to use their balance
sheet anymore. And people all signed up
to do this. Morgan Stanley to facilitate
$1.5 trillion in infrastructure
initiative.
The capital's there. Alphabet raises 25
billion this past week. Intel announces
a 15 billion stock offering for a
company that was worth less than a
hundred billion a year ago and they
raised it to 20 billion in the stock
traded higher than where the issuance
was. China is in the same race which
means the compute spending is happening
around the globe. You can go read the
little yellow lines but China and the US
are in a race. The government is still
trying to make sure that we don't lose
to China. So, exempts data center bonds
from key securization rules to make sure
that it's easier for data center owners
to sell asset back securities
potentially open the door for more debt
sales.
If you're looking for data center
delays, they're minor. We're still
moving forward on everything on the data
center side. Despite what you're reading
in the media, there are delays. I've
shown you guys my work on this. It's
already built into the way things are
being done. Nothing is a new surprise.
All of these are going on. They will be
delayed to some degree, but the capacity
is still coming online. It's not as fast
as it otherwise would be, but to be
honest with you, it doesn't really
matter because we don't have enough
memory anyway. So, all of these delays
are actually good because then we're not
over buying things or at least overusing
things before we get it in. So, the
delays allow the revenues to go a little
bit further out even though they've
committed to them. coreweave this week.
Very important in terms of going
through. You don't have to believe
anything they they say. You can go
through it, but again, I've got tons of
data that supports everything they say.
I think the most important thing to go
against things that you've heard from
Michael Bur and from Jim Chados in
particular, which I'll call out on this
because they don't ever turn around and
say, you know what, we were wrong. They
just keep saying, "No, this is this is
BS." They never change their mind ever.
It never there's no like it's a 70%
chance. It's always this is what's going
to happen. So if you pay for that at
least hopefully you pay for my stuff as
well where I'm going to spend time where
at this point I'm saying demand is
insatiable.
The A1 A100 is being contracted all the
way to 2029. This was introduced in
2020. They're saying they're completely
sold out. You can go through the
physical infrastructure itself has
scarcity value. So I've talked about you
want to invest in scarcity. So they were
originally saying two to three years may
be realistic. They're talking about it
being six to nine years now. New
generations will be gone because the old
one, we don't have enough data centers
being built that we can replace it
because the demand is greater than the
supply. It's like walking into a
supermarket. If they didn't have any
food but cans of sardines, you would
immediately love cans of sardines.
Even if that was the last thing you
wanted, that's what's happening is the
demand is too great. we have too many
agents buying or wanting and demanding
too many tokens. You guys can go through
the rest of this. The reality is it's
just the fact that on every level
whether it's pricing whether it's the
stuff we hear from them what we hear
from SpaceX what we hear from Google
what we see from Google on that point
with Google the article the uh podcast
to listen to this week Google's AI brain
drain from
the all-in podcast they talk a lot about
Google's reorganization framed it as a
capital allocation shift I'm going to
get into that a little bit more um
two-horse race according to David Saxs
completely agree AI infrastructure may
be the cleaner business than model
development. So, think of it this way.
Google's making a
decision similar to what Meta pushed out
there and SpaceX did, which is maybe we
should sell some of the compute since we
can't use it all right now and our
investors are getting angry with us
because free cash flow is going
negative. It's forcing you into
businesses that have a guaranteed ROIC
as opposed to chasing AGI. The problem
is the talent wants to chase AGI. So you
get Jeff Dean, you get Deis Sabis
possibly leaving. We've hit an important
inflection point now. And where this
shows up is if talents leaving,
multiples compress. Plain and simple. I
I don't see any any other way around it
unless Google can find some other
business. But the businesses that they'd
be creating that are new in my opinion
would have to be from the frontier model
side or at least that's my opinion to
higher probability.
Brad [clears throat] Gersonner gave a
huge com huge talk on this. Again,
Nvidia has financing limits, which is
why they rolled out all these companies
on there. Um, he talked about all of
these different things. Frontier Labs
are willing to overpay for compute
because there's shortages. Four times,
even five times market pricing to secure
large-scale compute. It gives them a
competitive advantage because other
people can't get it. So, the buyers are
concentrated because they have the
revenues coming in and they want to
secure the compute. And that's what he's
saying. This is very concentrated. So no
one's disagreeing that anthropic and
open AI are the cyclical nature. At the
same time, you have Nvidia doing a lot
of the lending to make sure that these
people can b buy their chips. It is
circular.
That's just the reality of what it is,
guys. And unfortunately, AI is a
completely different thing than anything
you've seen. Dennis Sabas wants to leave
Google, but he's staying. But they're
predicting he could leave within a year.
Again, it gets into the AGI side.
Moonshots went through this in detail in
two podcasts this week. One with Immad
Mustach, one with a kid named Kush.
I think Alex
said it best. Those who can't compete on
the frontier models go towards compute.
That's what Meta, that's what XAI, and
that's what Google did. And their models
are way behind the frontier models. The
frontier models are going to be
important. Open source models are going
to be important as well, but they may
Google may be winning distribution. So
they cover this as well. They talk about
the Sergey Brin side. You guys can
listen to it. I'll give you a couple
summaries towards the end. But the main
story is that Google's real business may
be the cloud and it may be
infrastructure. If that's the case, what
multiple should they have if it's not
Gemini? They may lose the model prestige
race and still make a lot of money from
AI infrastructure, but they may become
the Saudi Arabia OPEC
of compute while OpenAI, Anthropic, XAI,
and others compete on the intelligence
side.
Google's talent brand has deteriorated.
And this is where Kush comes in. He says
that for his MIT cohort and younger
builders, Google is no longer the dream
destination. The dream destinations are
now OpenAI, Anthropic, XAI, and Frontier
Labs. Unfortunately, that is the
reality. So, these companies
are different.
This is SpaceX. This is a private
company that's going public. This is
another private company. These are the
Frontier Labs.
This is the way it was for Google and
them before
they invented a lot of the modern AI but
the spiritual center of AI has moved
elsewhere. This is an important dynamic
and one of the reasons why in the
hyperscalers I will continue to say I
want to belong the receivers of the
capital because the infrastructure
demand is insatiable. These guys are
proving it because Google is seeing
talent leave because they don't have
enough compute. If they had enough
compute, they could do both the frontier
models and
the business side. But they can't. They
don't have enough compute. So they have
to allocate the resources, the scarce
resources somewhere. Google committed
roughly 200 billion capex this year to
compute infrastructure. That capital
earns a documented 30% ROIC is taxed
advantage through accelerated
depreciation is near certain demand
because the whole industry is compute
starved. Model development by contrast
requires tens of billions with a high
variance and no guaranteed return.
Again, this all gets into the argument
that was there. Now, I asked them to
take the transcript of the
Brad Gersonner one with the allimp pod
and then the the moonshots one. So,
these answers here and if you guys
haven't done this before, take all the
smart people and now you put them in one
table and you ask them a question. what
the Google shakeup reveals about compute
talent incentives and multi-state that's
the way that I like to go through these
things and then I go through through the
disruption side the syn synthesis for
all large companies the durable assets
of scale are capital physical
infrastructure distribution and
regulatory position the rational endgame
which Google is stumbling into or
engineering is the large company as
capital allocator and infrastructure
landlord to an ecosystem of
missiondriven vehicles is partly owns
companies that fight this trying to
retain everything internally will lose
the talent and keep the costs.
I subscribe to that entire view.
SpaceX semi analysis put this out. Um
Elon shocked the world again on SpaceX
first earning call saying 6 to8 gawatts
of incremental data centers in 2027
alone, possibly well above 10 gigs.
Sounds impossible, but we believe it. We
see SpaceX on track for about 10
gigawatts by year end 2027.
That's why SpaceX has value to the
company. And again, you should view the
other side as a call option. But Elon
Musk has already proved that he can
build data centers faster than anyone.
And the gigawatts are worth a lot of
money as we're seeing in terms of the
compute prices.
Um 80% of its output earmarked for
space-based data centers. So again, he's
doing a lot of stuff for terraab, which
is what I brought this up for. Terraab
is just confirmation of what's
happening. Just look at this thing that
he showed in terms of what the scale of
it will look like. I mean, you're
talking about him building something.
Elon Musk knows where the compute side
is and he's basically telling you I need
to build this which looks like a Star
Trek or a Star Wars situation and a
massive amount of land. He needs this
for the chips and in particular memory.
SpaceX goes exclusive with Nvidia
putting Ver Rubin GPUs in orbit. And
again, this was part of the reason why
when I talk about Nvidia and go through
it, he said, "We think the Ver Rubin
architecture is the best architecture.
We're exclusive to Nvidia." Yet, he's
building terra. So again, as you guys
are listening to this and I'm picking
out people that are just bearish on
this, I want to remind you. So for raas
this is the one pager that I'm now
sending to people to go through on why
my research is gear is geared towards
people to understand what's happening in
AI which to me cannot be covered by the
street you certainly cannot get research
that is put together
in a way like this know what has changed
and whether it matters to give all this
information there's a hundred slides put
together in this video today. I'm taking
you on a journey to make you learn
through data-driven stuff. You can go
upload this anywhere you want. You can
have your own agents bring it in. You
can go check everything I'm saying. You
can take the transcript. I do this every
week. I come with a hundred plus slides
every week of new information. I listen
to podcast relentlessly. And this way
you can go in and see what's changed on
a real-time basis. You can't get that
from the street. Know where it matters
and when it is turning. I not only give
you the names, but I spent the time, as
I'm going to show you soon, every week
doing this, telling you what I think the
riskreward is in the market. And if you
don't believe that, I'm going to show
you how you can do it on your own, and
give you a prompt to do it on your own.
The agency stuff is important. I'm
giving you prompts, which I'm giving you
one this week, workflows, Excel files
with all of the information on this,
tutorials on how you can put it to work
immediately, and hopefully things like
the Jensen Senuong knowledge brain,
which not only help you, but your kids,
which I've heard from them. But next
year,
starting in September, the next
constraint is not physical, it's
financial, the guard rails, consumer
agents, the settlement, it's stable
coins. the tokenization. This is going
to impact all of your portfolios,
the bridge between traditional
portfolios and unchanged assets. Your
client's holdings are what moves onto
these rails. You obviously have to learn
all this stuff before it happens. Reach
out to Mark.
Mark will guide you. Now,
I have said repeatedly in this that the
economic structure is changing, the
market structure is changing and the
earning structure is changing.
So earnings history, economics history,
market history, all of this stuff is
becoming useless. This is what this
whole thing is focused on. There is a
regime change that's happening. So if
you're listening to economists saying
the labor market is too strong, we have
to raise rates. Inflation is too high,
we have to raise rates. We are seeing a
disconnect here that has never happened
before. On the V side, the market
structure side with AI agents, we are
seeing tech momentum V up here while the
NDX V barely budges.
The earnings are growing rapidly.
Companies are able to grow earnings
because time is changing. This portfolio
is meant to show all of that. And again,
you're dealing with something that has
gone up massively,
had a consolidation, and has now bounced
back and made back 50%. I've given you
this in a 25 name, in a 10 name, in a
100 name, and then Morgan Stanley gives
you different ways to play it.
In terms of the reason that the street
can't cover it, the research firms are
all built vertically. They're built with
silos. There's a reason why I left
Morgan Stanley in 2001. And it wasn't
just because of 911. It was because 911
just recognized that life is too short.
And if my job as a 30-year-old who is
now firing people for a living is what
my life is going to be, I need to move
on. They can't cover everything
together. It's not possible. AI is not a
sector. It goes across industrials,
materials, chemicals, energy, power,
semiconductors.
Marll is not the same semiconductor as
Infinion, as Invidian, as Intel. They're
all different, guys, and you know that.
So, my job is to show you the structure
that's changed. The silos can't see
across them. the speed we're moving at
at least five times the speed of what
the world used to look like which makes
academics
any back test anything on earnings every
time we see earnings like this it's a
bubble okay but we're not hiring anyone
and there's usually hiring that's going
on before a bubble we're overhiring at
the bubbles
synthesis averages destroy the signal
too many people slow decision-m the
friction that goes in big companies is
the thing that is going to kill them
relative to AI native companies. I am an
A9 native company. Everything you're
seeing right now is created in AI and it
takes me a small amount of time to
create it. This is just the easiest way
to bring it to you. The organizational
structure that makes a firm excellent at
sector coverage is the structure that
makes it slow at a cross- sector regime
change. Those are the same property
viewed from two directions. So if you're
paying for research,
I'm giving you something what at a
minimum is different than what you're
getting from other people. It doesn't
mean it's better, but it's different.
And I guarantee you it's coming with new
stuff every week and new work every
week. This is the proof of this is the
NASDAQ returns year-to date 20%.
The 100 name portfolio
is up 46% 74 for the 25 name and 94 for
the 10 names. And the 10 names are good
10 names. They're highly correlated. In
fact, if you want the 10 names, I showed
this on the week the subscriber webinar
this week. Equal weighted average return
103. So I showed you 94. Um median
return is 65. The best performer is up
249%. The worst one is up 16 and a half.
That's Nvidia. It's outperforming the
S&P by 13%. Eight of the 10 are up more
than 40%. The average return is about
7.9 times the S&P's year-to- date
return. The median is five times. From a
valuation perspective with where we are
right now, the average forward PEG ratio
is 0.8. The median is 081. This is for
the 10 names despite being up 103% year
to date. This is all happening because
earnings growth is growing rapidly. The
median next year forecast for earnings
growth 40%. Seven of the 10 names have
expected earnings growth of over 30. Why
would you go hunting for names?
This is going to continue because the
demand for compute is insatiable. the
multiples can compress. And when we go
through this, again, my job in doing
this as someone who thinks in riskreward
is to turn more negative when it seems
like things are due for a consolidation,
navigating the AI midcycle slowdown on
June 8th.
So, here's the prompt, guys. Take my
transcripts, as many as you want. I did
everything from May on to just highlight
to you guys something. and you just take
the prompt. It'll be uploaded this
weekend. Its job is analyze a
chronological series of weekly market
commentary transcripts to determine how
the speaker's long-term market
conviction, short-term outlook, and
willingness to take investment risks are
changing over time. This is an unbiased
thing. You guys can do it on your own.
It's a prompt that goes through, and I'm
going to show you the results. You can
do this not with mine, but I'm sure
there's other podcasts you listen to on
a weekly basis. Go measure their tone.
All of this is supposed to do is to
trans. So what it does is on a
structural basis I'm staying bullish the
entire time. On a tactical basis it's
shifting. So I believe computer is
insatiable. I want to be in this trade
for the next three to five years. But I
want to be tactical and make sure my
risk is lower when the tactical level is
low and the riskreward is low. Selective
risk reduction in May. So this is the
risk posture is saying this is the cycle
stage. I said we're in parabolic
exhaustion in memory. Selective risk
reduction. You guys can go through
defensive selective risk neutral
consolidation.
Here's just some of the stages. This
what I said on May 17th. I've been
scaling out of things. I'm effectively
as far as I'm concerned out of
everything. Definitely out of all
micron. So, if people call me up and say
they bought in at May 17th or they did
whatever, I'm trying to give you guys a
riskreward on what's happening and
trying to go capital preservation or
capital rotation. Rotation with a
genuine reduction in portfolio beta. I
was talking about the need for
deleveraging. The d-risking goes from
partial to near total in the crowded
leg. So again, if you don't believe what
I'm saying, here's what this will do for
you. So this is taking all of those
numbers and I overlaid my thematic
portfolio. So for those of you
particularly the asset managers who I
speak to regularly.
This is a way for you to incept and see
how I'm doing. So I start going into a
more cautious. This is a yellow light.
This doesn't mean bail out of
everything. This means I'm getting more
cautious. I'm reducing my micron. The
red side is when it's like stop putting
anything to work right now. I'm getting
more worried. I'm seeing signs. This is
what happened in those meetings. Every
one of these dots is one of the videos.
It's the transcripts. Then I start
becoming back to neutral. And then the
first time that I start saying that I'm
buying stuff, which is when Micron broke
below 900 is in here. And now you start
seeing the green dots where I'm starting
to turn more positive. So back in here,
what I was saying is we need a
consolidation. I was showing you
consolidations, price and time. Even
here, I was still saying we will never
be able to pick a bottom. So, those of
you who want me to try and pick this or
this, nobody can do that and certainly
not me. And I don't try to do that. What
I want to do is reduce risk in here and
then add back when I think there's been
enough panic and enough consolidation.
So I'm looking for a combination of and
this is what makes these green there is
I you start hearing me say I think we're
closer to capitulation. I'm seeing the
VIX go higher. I'm seeing this go on.
I'm hearing about this. Then situational
awareness happens and then all of a
sudden I give a very positive sign on
things and say I believe that's it. The
riskreward is now shifted. You can use
that create your own. And during that
entire consolidation, I was creating the
consolidation playbook to try and put
people in a position. Two, three weeks
ago, the week right before situational
awareness, I put something out said
combing through the rubble to give you
guys the ability to go find stuff. So,
here's what's happened. We've now
already made back over 50% of the fall.
This was a situational awareness day.
So, again, my goal is not to pick you
tops and bottoms. It's actually to help
you navigate through to stay with the
structural trend to minimize losses and
maximize gains. Plain and simple. That's
the name of the game. You maximize
gains. You try to find things with a
riskreward in your favor where you feel
like things have been cleansed. And
that's why that 50-day rate of change
and some of the tools that I showed in
the subscriber webinar, which I'm
working on, which are algorithms to time
the risk side. So, I'm taking what I
just showed you and I'm incorporating
all of that stuff into an algorithm to
hopefully give you a score to show you
where I think the risk is. For those of
you who've never gone, I have my website
now. I just wanted to show you this for
one reason. Okay, it's visserlabs.com.
Great. Here's my logo. That's a linear
move. That's an exponential move.
Academic over here, entrepreneurs over
here. The main thing about this, when
you go to my website, I want you to go
there. Took me one hour to build. Took
me about a day to work with network
solutions to get it up where I secured
the domain of visserlabs.com.
But it took me literally about an hour
to build the website. So I'm telling you
this because when Network Solutions did
a scoring on it, it got a hundred out of
a hundred.
If you use AI and you use it properly,
all I did was put prompts in to build
the site. It's not perfect. It still
needs some changes, but it works, guys.
You can build stuff like that. And
that's gets back. My job here is to help
you guys prepare for the future, not
just an in AI to navigate this, to deal
with the the parabas and the bubbles and
everything that happens, but it's also
to make you smarter and how to use it
and to prepare you for this. The next
constraint is financial crypto rails for
AI agents. I'm telling you, mark my
words. You guys want to reach out in a
year when I'm wrong, it's going to be
because of that. So, one company that
reported Figure.
I talked about Figure a lot with Anthony
Pompiano this week. I highly recommend
watching the video this week. I think we
got into some interesting topics, but
more importantly, my brain was kind of
firing today on a lot of different
things involving time, which is where my
focus is. I'm spending a lot more time
with the crypto community. I'm speaking
at more um places. I'll be speaking at
the Pomp event. I'll be speaking at a
Bitcoin Policy Institute event in DC. A
lot of things are going on. I probably
did four had four podcasts released this
week that had me speaking on it. We're
at the stage now, guys, where I'll be
doing more crypto stuff and you're going
to be seeing more stuff. So, go to the
site, go to the web page, but figure is
a perfect example of how this is
starting already. Figure released
earnings consumer loan marketplace
volume was up 4 was 4.3 billion, up 132%
year-over-year. The tokenized onchange
marketplace figure connect is now
expected to approach 70% of volume. We
are building the modern capital
marketplace amidst the paradigm shift in
the capital markets towards tokenization
and standardization. This is happening
now guys. This is why I built this. This
is my ecosystem
correlated with Bitcoin.
This is the year-to-day performance. So,
it's normalized. If I didn't normalize
it, this would be a direct overlay.
except you see the ecosystem is trading
better than here. I've added some more
names in here. I'm working with a bunch
of crypto people. If anyone wants to
reach out and they want to be involved
in this process, I'm enjoying doing
this. I need I have 10 verticals. I have
about four names to five names in each.
There's about 45 names in the index.
Bitcoin is a representation of the S&P
500 of the future. I will continue to
say that to anyone who wants to listen.
Figure is part of this.
Humans will be rounding error on the
internet. Bot traffic will exceed human
traffic by a factor of 1,000 within five
years. Elon Musk on cloudfire's forecast
AI agentic internet traffic will
obviously vastly exceed human usage.
Guys, go make money on that.
Transactions are going to happen. Stable
coin card spending volume surge another
16%. 16%.
You want to do an ARR on that?
US bank regulator opens national
charters to Bitcoin and crypto firms.
The SEC is about to cook while Congress
is stuck arguing over the Clarity Act.
Just like AI, nothing stops crypto,
guys. It will continue. Even if it's
not, the Clarity Act's not done. So, if
you're waiting for the Clarity Act or
it's thinking there's going to be a sell
the news moment on this, I'm telling
you, a year from now, we are going to
have a volume explosion on this stuff.
We don't know where all markets are
going to be, but I do know that volumes
will be expanding. financial guardrails
will be connected. I wrote this and
released it both on Substack this week's
and my subscriber website. I released it
because it's something I believe is
really important. This is around the yen
intervention.
It is a connection of everything
happening between AI mac uh the macro
side in terms of the debt, the deficit,
Japan's debt, the US debt. This goes
through all of it. It is meant to
realize that in my opinion, we will look
back on the week of situational
awareness where we had the dollar yen
intervention and we had Kevin Worsh
basically losing credibility according
to people
and Lewis Gau put this piece out this
week like me. He released it to
everyone. He does not do that. I don't
do that for my subscribers stuff, but
that's how important um the week was for
me. And then he gets into something
equally as important on the exact same
theme, which is why I wanted to show you
guys. But this is the most important
thing. And he said, "AI and stable coins
could reshape rather than simply destroy
dollar dominance." Gavka raises the
provocative idea of a compute dollar
replacing the petro dollar. That word
compute again. Insatiable demand for
compute, an insatiable race for both
compute and owning the crypto landscape.
AI is becoming more than a technology
story. computers evolving into an
industrial resource, a geopolitical
asset and potentially a pillar of the
monetary system. This is on the other
side of the debt world where we just
continue to do whatever is necessary to
keep the debt going and keep spending.
Bessence, whatever it takes, yenval mass
limited firepower. This is the reason
it's so important because they whether
it's yield curve control, whether it's
raising the cap on FEMA and them getting
invol, it doesn't really matter. Scott
is up against it. He didn't create this
problem, but they're trying to race out
of it. And the problem is they're not
getting the receipts and they're
spending their way out. So, the debt and
the deficit are just not getting better
fast enough, even if they are getting
better at all. Wall Street sees a bond
market angst and we're seeing that the
bond market just won't rally. We had a
week where the inflation data surprised
on the downside. Retail sales missed. We
had a week before where the jobs number
missed. And yet long-term yields are
just not coming down. They're not going
up either, but they're not coming down.
And the yen is also not moved much since
the intervention. And that's despite the
fact that now we're down to 31% for
September for Wor
and 80% for the BOJ. These numbers were
about 5050 each before the payroll
numbers. Now we're at here and yet we're
still not seeing any change. Now, I
happen to believe this is a mistake by
the markets and you should be buying the
the basement trade. You should be buying
gold, buying silver, buying Bitcoin. But
regardless of that until we start seeing
yields come down, it's just not
happening. So, the Worsh attacks
continue. And he's going to be speaking
at Jackson Hole. This came out from Bill
Dudley. Worsh implied that the PCE index
could be jettisoned as the Fed's primary
inflation metric as soon as January. Who
knows come after January he might say
about a strategy he said I suspect the
task force might have something that
the reason I wanted you guys to read
this this is academic this is exactly
the problem this is what Kevin Walsh
that's what that whole paper I wrote is
that the academic fed
does not exist you cannot focus on the
academic fed this be bank of America
after the CPI is still calling for three
right hikes this year
holding firm
At least Canro understands. Okay, so
here's what the Fed is saying. So this
is Fed speak chart overlaid with a
leading indicator which is the labor
plus inflation surprise index which has
now come down. We'll see if this goes.
But this is the reason why at this point
we haven't seen rates come down. So the
question is is Walsh going to give any
guidance or do anything that helps?
two-year rates have come down just
because the probabilities have come
down. They did break the 50-day moving
average after being above it for one of
the longest times in the last decade.
We'll see if it goes. But this is why I
wrote this. The academic Fed, a secular
regime shift, it's far more powerful. It
usually reflects dramatic changes in
monetary policy, fiscal policy, and
innovation. I believe we were in the
early stages of one. That is what the AI
trade is within that paper. Despite or
what your favorite Oh, this is inside my
uh other paper. Despite what your
favorite economist may tell you while
looking through a historical lens and
assuming the old relationships still
hold, something has changed. AI is
already disrupting the labor market and
the rise of AI agents is only beginning.
If you look at the labor market
contextually, it is very weak. That gets
back to the chart I showed you with the
S&P earnings relative to year-over-year
labor.
So again,
research firms are b built vertically.
Academics seldom change their view.
That's what entrepreneurs do. That's
what traders do. Hopefully that's the
way you view the work that I do. I like
to be bearish equally as bullish if I
think it's going to save me money. You
can't get away from this divergence. So
if you're an academic, highlight this
and tell me why this isn't a fair way to
look at things. The labor market is very
weak. while we are growing earnings at
32%. We've never seen anything like this
before and we're not coming out of a
recession. Here's more in the labor
market. I showed this last week. I just
want to re-emphasize it. I don't see
anyone doing this. This is the sixmonth
rate of change on the aggregate weekly
payrolls, which takes into account
weekly hours, the wage growth, plus a
number of job hires. A much broader and
better way of looking at the payroll
market. And we're at the weakest
six-month rate of change since 12, 2012,
14 years ago. Here is the job creation
right now for non-farm payrolls. X
healthcare and leisure. I don't like
doing X things, but I do want to show it
as these things are both related to old
people that the boomers who have money.
So health care and travel, that's great
except for one thing. Those are the jobs
that can't be replaced by AI.
So you have a very difficult situation.
Here's the non-farm payrolls again
year-over-year. So we're sitting down
here because
of AI agents.
This is the weekly ADP numbers. So we
had a jump here. This is when the Fed
speak changed. This is when you saw the
December rate hikes be built in. Well,
now the non-farm the ADP numbers just
keep weakening every week.
We're not adjusting anything. Here's the
labor force participation rate, which
just continues to go down. If we're
losing labor supply,
that's 10ear rates overlaid with it. Why
aren't wages going up? I saw someone
write something this week. Look at this.
An uptick. Are you kidding me? So, the
Atlanta the Atlanta Fed wage thing, this
is a hookup. The hourly earnings we just
saw from the uh non-farm payrolls
dropped to 3.2%.
The Atlanta Fed is at the same level it
was before 2020. So is the hourly
earnings. So is the quits rate.
Give me something that shows. We know
that if we're not getting wage growth
that is significant to offset the weekly
hours not increasing and the fact that
we're losing labor force participation
rate and we're not hiring any people. I
don't see why the Fed should be raising
rates especially not three times. I
don't even understand what that is. Um
if their mandate is labor and inflation.
So let's go through the second part of
it. the inflation data. So, we're going
to follow Bill Dudley on this PCE thing.
I think Kevin Worsh has it right. Here's
PCE all on the same scale, guys. PCE
core and here are the other core
numbers. Plus,
this doesn't include true inflation. So,
I left them out of it just because it's
way down here below two. all of these
other gauges, whether it's the sticky,
the Atlanta sticky CPI core, which is at
2.5, the CPI core, which is 2.6, the
Dallas trim mean, which is 2.2. They
just made a change in the way they're
calculating it, 2.4, whatever. Cleveland
2.7, only the PCE core, that one point
is up there. Sounds like it's not a good
one to use. Here are the inflation swaps
relative to core CPI, lower. Why aren't
these being talked about as mattering? I
took all of those ones I just showed you
on the prior screen, not the swaps, the
one before this, and I put them as one
index. That's what this number is. That
was taking those four and averaging them
together. That's 2.5. This is PCE core.
This is it over time. There's two things
to note. Number one, during the prior
from 1990
to 2020, the white line stayed above the
orange line all the time.
So if you normalize this and again
contextually this number should be down
here based on history, something has
changed in this calculation.
Kevin, you want me to work on the Fed,
give me a call. I'm happy to help you
guys with some of this stuff to make
sure we're not making decisions based on
uh people on Wall Street academics
telling you what you should do. Real
rates, the white line here. Real
two-year yields are up here. Here's the
debasement trade. This is gold, silver,
and Bitcoin. And the dollar, the dollar
has already responded. It was down again
today. This is before today. So, it's
already down here at new lows. Gold has
moved. Silver has moved. Bitcoin has not
moved yet. That's the green line here.
It's still sitting there. Eventually, it
will. I don't know when. We'll see.
Academics ask, "When does the evidence
tell us has happened under comparable
conditions?" Markets ask, "What's going
to happen before everyone else realizes
it?" This is the money-making side.
Entrepreneurs ask, "What becomes
possible now that wasn't possible
before?" That is the AI native world.
That is the world we speak about on
Visser Labs. Now, finally, China added
20 tons of gold in July, its largest
monthly purchase since October 2023.
China's central bank adds gold to Hong
Kong as well. And finally, the Bank of
Korea resumes gold investment after 13
years. Korea is back in the game. AI is
becoming more than a technology story.
Computers evolving into an industrial
resource, a geopolitical asset, and
potentially a pillar of the monetary
system. Thank you, Lewis Gav. Thank you
to all of you guys. I will see you maybe
from New York next week, maybe still
here. I hope it's still here, but I
don't know.